One man is copying the most notorious killers in history one at a time.
Together, two women must stop him from killing again. Or they’re next.
Copycat is a thriller, crime, mystery film directed by Jon Amiel.
An agoraphobic psychologist and a female detective must work together to take
down a serial killer who copies serial killers from the past.
Helen Hudson, played by Sigourney Weaver.
M.J. Monahan, played by Holly Hunter.
Ruben Goetz, played by Dermot Mulroney.
Peter Foley, played by William McNamara.
Daryll Lee Cullum, played by Harry Connick Jr..
Lt. Quinn, played by J.E. Freeman.
Copycat is a 1995 American psychological thriller horror film directed by Jon Amiel
and starring Sigourney Weaver, Holly Hunter, and Dermot Mulroney.
The score was composed by Christopher Young.
The film follows a criminal psychologist and a homicide detective who must work together to find a
serial killer who is committing copycat crimes modeled after notorious murderers.
Principal photography began on October 3, 1994, in the San Francisco Bay Area.
The film was theatrically released by Warner Bros.
on October 27, 1995.
It was a moderate box office success and received positive reviews for
the performances of its leads, writing, and direction.
It proved very successful in the video rental market, becoming the
11th most-rented film in the United States for 1996.
The film explores themes of police brutality, psychology,
police operation, police protection, psychologist.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and intense.